Alejandro Iván Villegas Partida

CDMX, Iztapalapa • alejandrovillegas.hu@gmail.com • $\underline{linkedin.com/in/alejandro-ivan} \bullet \underline{github.com/ivanhue}$

About me

Software Developer with over 2 years of experience. I have worked with different technologies and have shown strong ability to adapt to new environments. I am good at solving problems, organizing tasks, and helping to maintain a positive and collaborative work atmosphere.

Experience

Media Aérea Remote Full Stack Nov 2023 – Currently

- Developed web applications using Django (MVT architecture), leveraging JavaScript and Python to enhance functionality and performance.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs, created endpoints, and documented processes with Swagger, ensuring adherence to best practices.
- Optimized database queries through Django's ORM, improving data retrieval and application efficiency.
- Utilized Docker to streamline development environments and ensure consistent deployment across systems.
- Managed version control and collaboration using Git, facilitating efficient team workflows and code management.
- Utilized CMMI framework for iterative development, progress presentations, and continuous feedback to enhance project quality and alignment.

Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana System Support Specialist

CDMX, Iztapalapa Feb - 2023

- Provided technical support to students and faculty, troubleshooting and resolving issues to ensure seamless
 operation.
- Automated processes, reducing manual workload and saving significant hours of work.
- Organized and managed databases, ensuring data integrity and efficient access.
- Deployed web applications, ensuring smooth and efficient rollout for end-users.
- Managed direct client interactions, handled ambiguity, and ensured requirement fulfillment through effective communication and problem-solving.

RedPoint Artificial Intelligence Developer

Remote Nov 2022 – Feb 2023

- Object detection and classification (Computer vision).
- Utilization of Raspberry Pi for machine learning projects.
- Project documentation.
- Database management.

Education

Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana Bachelor of Computer Science

CDMX, Iztapalapa Feb - 2023

• GPA: 3.5/4.0

Thesis: Human Posture Detection using AI tools

• Relevant Coursework: Chatbot Development

Leadership, Activities & Certifications

Neuroscience researcher CINVESTAV

Research Assistant

Apr 2023 - May 2023

- Analysis of data produced by experiments in the rat hippocampus.
- Optimization of laboratory workflow using new technologies.

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification

Jul - 2022

Certification

• Build machine learning models in Python using popular machine learning libraries NumPy & scikit-learn

IEEE Computer Society

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

President

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams on social impact projects, contributing to successful outcomes.
- Planned and delivered workshops, courses, and talks to provide support and guidance to students.

Microsoft Azure AZ900 Certification (Cloud Computing)

Jan - 2022

Certification

• Foundational knowledge of cloud concepts and Microsoft Azure

Skills & Interests

Technical: Python, Javascript, SQL, Docker, Git, Linux commands.

Language: English B1/B2

Soft skills: Teamwork, adaptability, conflict resolution, time management.

Interests: Cloud, backend, devops, good practices, linux.